Guide to the Lincoln Steffens Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III. Letters of Lincoln Steffens
  - Steffens, Lincoln
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November?, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November 11, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November 12, (a.l., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November 13, (a.l.s.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November 15, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November [18], (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November 19, (a.l., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November 20, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November 21, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November 22, (a.l., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November 23, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November 25, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November 26? [sic], (a.l., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November 28, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November 28, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November [28], (a.l., 4p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 November 30, (a.l.s., 3p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December 1, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 74)
    - To [Ella Winter], 1932 December 3, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December 3?, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December [3], (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December [4], (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December? 6, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December 7, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December 7?, (a.l., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December 10, (a.l.s., 6p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December 11, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December 14, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December 16, (a.l.s.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December 16, (a.l.s.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December 22, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December 23, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December 24, (a.l.s., 6p.) (Box 74)
    - To [Ella Winter], 1932 December 25, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December 26, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December 29, (a.l., 2p., signed, with postscript, by Pete Stanley Steffens) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, 1932 December 31, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 74)
    - To Ella Winter, circa 1933, (a.l., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To [Ella Winter], 1933, (a.l.s., 2p., fragment, last two pages only of a longer letter) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 January?, (a.l.s., 1p., with address in the hand of Ella Winter on the verso) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 January 1, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 January 2, (a.l., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, [1933 January 4], (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 January 6, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 January 14, (a.l.s., 6p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 January 16, (a.l., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 January 22, (a.l., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 January 25, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 January 29, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 January 31, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To [Ella Winter], circa 1933 February, (a.l.s., 2p., fragment, postscript of a longer letter) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 February 2, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 February 4?, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 February 6, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 February 7, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, circa 1933 February 9, (a.l.s., 1p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 February 12, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 February 12, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 February 16-17, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Mrs. A. (Frieda) Winter, 1933 February 18, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 February 18, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 February 21, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, circa 1933 March, (a.l.s., 2p., fragment, pages 1 and 2 are missing) (Box 75)
    - To Editor of the New York World-Telegram, circa 1933 March, (a.l., 2p., enclosed with the above letter) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 March 1, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 March 5, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 March 11, (a.l.s., 6p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 March 14, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 March 16, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 March 16, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 March 22, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 March 23, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 March 25, (a.l., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 March 30, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 April 2, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 April 6, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 April 9, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 April 14, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 April 18, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 April 19, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 April 21, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 April 24, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 April 25, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 May?, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933? May, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 [May?] 2, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 May 3, (a.l., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 May 10, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 May 13, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 May 16, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 May 17, (a.l.s., 1p.) (Box 75)
    - To Mrs. A. (Frieda) Winter, 1933 May 19, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 May 19, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 May 20, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 June 3, (a.l.s., 2p., fragment) (Box 75)
    - To Mrs. A. (Frieda) Winter, 1933 June 29, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 August 16, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 August 20, (a.l.s.) (Box 75)
    - To Edward A. Filene, 1933 September 28, (t.l. copy?, 1p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 October 19, (a.l.s., 3p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 November 12?, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 November 21?, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 November 23, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 November 24-25, (a.l.s., 5p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 November 25, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Pete Stanley Steffens, 1933 November 26, (a.l.s., 3p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 November 27, (a.l.s., 6p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 November 27-28, (a.l., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, [1933 November 30], (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, [1933 November 30], (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 December 1, (a.l.s., 5p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 December 2, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, [1933 December 3], (a.l., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, [1933 December 4], (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 December 4, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, [1933 December 5], (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, [1933 December 6], (a.l.s., 6p.) (Box 75)
    - To Pete Stanley Steffens, circa [1933 December 7], (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 December 7, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 December 8-9, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Ella Winter, 1933 December 11, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 75)
    - To Dot Steffens Hollister (Mrs. John James), 1934 April 4, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
    - To Mrs Wood, 1934 July 5, (t.l.s.) (Box 75)
      (Mrs. Wood may be Sara Bard Field)
    - To Frances Perkins, 1934 July 19, (t.l.s., 1p., draft) (Box 75)
    - To Mrs. A. (Frieda) Winter, 1934 September 24, (t.l., 2p., typed signature, with manuscript corrections) (Box 75)
    - To Pete Stanley Steffens, 1936 July 8, (t.l., 1p., typed signature) (Box 75)
    - To Pete Stanley Steffens, 1936 July 13, (t.l., 1p., typed signature, with notes in the hand of Ella Winter) (Box 75)
    - To Pete Stanley Steffens, 1936 July 21, (t.l., 2p., typed signature, with manuscript corrections) (Box 75)
  - Suggett, Laura Steffens--To Phebe M. Rideout, 1920 May 14, (t.l., 1p.) (Box 75)
  - Sutliff, Helen--To Laura Steffens Suggett (2nd Mrs. Allen H.), 1918 April 18, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
  - Towne, Charles Hanson--To Lincoln Steffens, 1915 June 25, (t.l.s., 1p., with copy of related letter) (Box 75)
  - Wheeler, Howard D.--To Lincoln Steffens, 1916 July 17, (t.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
  - Winter, Ella
    - To Mrs. A. (Frieda) Winter, 1925 February 27, (a.l.s., 4p., signed "Pete") (Box 75)
    - To Dot Steffens Hollister (Mrs. John James), 1926 September 23, (a.l.s.) (Box 75)
    - To [Fremont] Older, 1926 November 4, (a.l.s., 4p., with copy of related letter) (Box 75)
    - To Laura Steffens Suggett (2nd Mrs. Allen H.), 1927 July 31-August 3, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 75)
  - Miscellaneous Folders
    - Rider, Fremont--Correspondence (Copies) (Box 75)
    - Suggett, Laura Steffens
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence re: Real Estate, 1921 (Box 75)
      - School Honor Roll, 1884 (Box 75)
    - Miscellaneous Material (Box 75)
- Series IV. Additional Correspondence and Manuscripts
  Series IV consists of drafts of letters from Steffens to Bennett Cerf, George Creel, Sam Darcy and Frank Khox, 1 letter to him from Alan Suggett and 1 from Charles Erskine Scott Wood; drafts of manuscripts by Steffens of his Autobiography, parts I-IV; of speeches and magazine articles; columns for local California newspapers, 1928-1934, commentaries on the San Francisco strike of 1934; on current events and the state of American cities; and articles about children, (4 boxes)
  - Cataloged Correspondence and Manuscripts
    (This material is not on microfilm)
    - Drafts of letters from Lincoln Steffens to
      - Cerf, Bennett (Box 76)
      - Creel, George (Box 76)
      - Darcy, Sam (Box 76)
      - Knox, Frank (Box 76)
    - Suggett, Alan--To Lincoln Steffens, (1 a.l.s.) (Box 76)
  - Cataloged Manscripts
    - Manuscripts by Lincoln Steffens, A-Z (Box 76)
    - Incomplete and Unidentified Manuscripts and Notes (Box 76)
    - Autobiography of Lincoln Steffens (Box 77-79)
      (This material is also available on the microfilm reel for Series IV.)